Thomas Calle

Software Development Full Stack Web Developer

Toronto, Ontario | Phone: (647) 405-3196 | Email: thos.calle@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/thomas-calle | Website: https://thomascalle.github.io/7homas7he7ank-React-Portfolio/

PROFILE SUMMARY

Highly qualified and motivated Full Stack Web Developer, recently graduated from the University of Toronto's Computer Science Bootcamp April 2023, seeking a junior developer or internship position to enhance my technical skills and understanding of project management principles. With 14 years of demonstrated experience in business operations, customer service, and human resources, I specialize in merging technical expertise with superior interpersonal communication across all management levels. Dedicated to continuous learning and eager to contribute to and advance within your esteemed organization.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend | • HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, React, D3.js, Node.js, API Integration, Styled-Components.

Backend | • MySQL, NoSQL, Python, C#, MongoDB, Scratch, Express.js, Node.js, API integration.

Methodologies | • Agile Methodology, Scrum, Kanban, Routes, Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), Object Relational, Mapping(ORM), API Integration, GraphQL, MERN, Wireframe Design, E-Commerce, SEO.

Developer Tools | • Visual Studio Code, Git, GitHub, GitLab, Heroku, Apollo, HRIS, Microsoft Azure, Microsoft Office 365, MongoDB Compass, Mongo DB Atlas, NPM, Insomnia, Command Line Interface(CLI).

Operating Systems | • Windows, macOS, iOS.

EDUCATION

University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada

Jan 2023 - Apr 2023

- Degree: Computer Science: Software Developer, Full Stack Web Developer (Accelerated Boot Camp)
- Graduated top of class (4.0 GPA)
- Relevant Curriculum: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Git, GitHub, MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Front-end, Back-end, Full Stack, MERN Stack, DOM, MVC, ORM, CLI, PWA's, OOP, jQuery, Bootstrap, API, SQL, MySQL, GraphQL, SWE, SDLC, Agile Methodology (SCRUM & Kanban), UI/UX Design, Principles, Wireframe, Responsive Web Design & Web Accessibility.

PROJECTS

Full-Stack Engineer & Architect | Human Resources SQL Employee Tracker

Jan 2023 - Apr 2023

Command Line Interface(CLI) SQL Database Management Application

GitHub | JavaScript | Node.js | Inquirer | MySQL

Project Link: https://github.com/ThomasCalle/Thomas-SQL-Employee-Tracker

- **SQL Database Management:** Developed a command-line interface(CLI) application, leveraging Node.js, Inquirer.js, and MySQL2, to facilitate dynamic CRUD operations on an SQL Human Resources employee database tracker.
- User-Centric CLI: Engineered user-friendly (CLI) that enables both developers & non-developers to seamlessly manage employee data, emphasizing a deep understanding of user experience(UX) and the translation of complex operations into user-friendly prompts.

Full-Stack Engineer & Architect | Model View Controller(MVC) Chess Blog

Jan 2023 - Apr 2023

Content management system(CMS) web application.

GitHub | Express | JavaScript | Handlebars | ORM | MVC

Project Link: https://github.com/ThomasCalle/Thomas-Model-View-Controller-MVC-Tech-Blog

- **Developed and Deployed:** CMS-style platform on Heroku, incorporating (CRUD) operations for blog posts and comments, structured around the (MVC) for creating and managing persistent storage for a seamless user experience.
- Optimized User Experience & Security: Strategically designed intuitive user interface, navigation and interactivity by implemented berypt for robust password hashing, safeguarding user credentials and upholding stringent data protection standards.
- **Comprehensive Web Framework:** Merged Node.js, Express.js, and Sequelize ORM for a responsive backend infrastructure, paired with Handlebars.js for UI rendering, and bolstered security mechanisms via express-session.

Full-Stack Engineer, Scrum Lead | 10 Things to do in Toronto

Jan 2023 - Apr 2023

Interactive Front-end web application

GitHub | HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript | API | Agile

Project Link: https://github.com/ThomasCalle/10-Things-To-Do-In-Toronto

- Accessibility: developed responsive design across multiple devices, emphasizing accessibility tailored for the visual impaired.
- **Technical Integration:** seamlessly integrated Server-Side APIs with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, ensuring a dynamic and user-friendly interface. Emphasized professional best practices in web development for both desktop and mobile users.
- Agile Methodologies: synchronized resource allocation, effective data logging, and alignment with Agile Manifesto. Record kept Kanban Board to monitor collaborative efforts, to ensure team success of vision of Minimum Viable Product (MVP).

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Digital Marketing and Branding Manager

December 2021 – Present

Self Employed, Client @hasbulla.hushetskiy | Toronto, Ontario

Project Link: https://www.instagram.com/ar/245529254340388/

- Developed the "Hasbulla Filter" on META's platforms: Instagram & Facebook, achieving +16.4 million impressions and +335,000 shares, significantly boosting market and branding visibility for Instagram Celebrity Client @hasbulla.hushetskiy.
- Managed and promoted the "Hasbulla Filter", initially increasing consumer impressions by +389,353 views within the first month, and by an additional +413.56% in the second month, totaling +2 million views, enhancing engagement for @hasbulla.hushetskiy.
- Conducted Market Analysis Research, informing strategic position, achieving +16.4 million impressions from Dec 2021 to Present.
- Collaborated with B2B partners to enhance SEO and AR Filter functionality, resulting in a +4798.51% increase in platform impressions, by creating community updates on Meta and Discord, fostering positive community marketing and branding initiatives.

Marketing and Branding Model

December 2022 – Present

Orange Model & Talent Management Inc. | Toronto, Ontario

- Leveraged + 14 years of Customer Service and Business Operations experience, with modeling experience, to excel in enhancing B2B partners' marketing and branding strategies thereby amplifying national reach and impact of campaign projects at Orange Model.
- Promoted Diversity and Inclusion (D&I) through proactive PR, enhancing Equality & Representation in modelling campaigns.

Human Resources Director Assistant

May 2022 - November 2022

Skills for Change | Toronto, Ontario

- Managed entire HR department throughout the Director of HR's absence, assuming full responsibility of administrative functions, maintaining compliance with policies and procedures, demonstrating proficiency in HRIS software utilization.
- Arbitrated matters from part-time employees to executives, ensuring alignment and delivering daily strategic reports to the CEO.
- Coordinated and facilitated successful recruitment and onboarding of (45) students, (4) entry-level, (3) mid-level, (4) senior-level, and (2) executive-level professionals, deploying payroll, database entry, records and leading training and development orientation events to ensure compliance, compensation, vulnerable sector checks.
- Created a company-wide Mental Health & Wellness initiative by organizing and presenting weekly "Wellness Wednesday" events, fostering supportive company culture, these (1) hour Zoom conferences held an average attendance of 18+ employees weekly.

Account Management Administration

May 2020 - May 2022

Switch Health, Government of Ontario | Toronto, Ontario

- Executed account management and data entry of client Covid-19 immunology records by fortifying corporate communication and customer relations, relaying accurate info on the Covid-19 Global Pandemic, minimizing B2B partners and customers discrepancies.
- Surpassed regional customer health conflict and resolution management, achieving volumes +51% greater than employee average aiding approximately (+150 to +250 weekly, +600 to +1000 monthly) reported illnesses.

Management, Supervisor

May 2017 – October 2019

Liberty Entertainment Group Ltd. | Toronto, Ontario

- Optimized HR and Payroll Process via ADP Software: Administered Payroll, Time & Attendance protocols for over 100 employees, resolving discrepancies swiftly, which elevated operational efficiency and streamlined daily workflows.
- Streamlined Recruitment & Onboarding Process by creating personalized mentorship program and training sessions, where new hires received operational workflows, to assimilate new hires, reducing potential setbacks and fostering confidence in the workplace.

Merchandise & Retail Sales Associate Lead

March 2011 – July 2017

Maple Leaf Sports & Entertainment Ltd. (MLSE) | Toronto, Ontario

- Advanced in Customer Relations, Team Management and Company Culture: leaving an everlasting impression culminating (3) promotions: Co-op, Intern, Merchandiser, and Lead Associate.
- Lead a team of +5employees daily optimizing Organizational Development(OD) by fostering trust, collaboration, and effective communication propelling teamwork in workplace culture to drive (KPI) sale achievements.
- Requested to Lead +16 Seasonal Onboarding, Recruitment & Development Training sessions by Department Head: through hands-on-leadership with modelling behaviour that brought an effective recruiting program to ensure new hires exceed day-to-day operations and employee potential.
- \bullet Surpassed Sales Standards becoming highest grossing store to raise Sale Analytics of units-per-transaction sold from (1.8) to (2.3) under high occupancy events of +20,000 customers.
- Honored with +15 Customer Service & Satisfaction Awards (pool of 130 staff) and (2) Corporate-wide Employee of the Year Awards (pool of 2,500+ staff).

Page: 2 of 2